Hey, Rin.
Wake up.
Come here.
It was just a dream.
Don't worry about it.
Huh?
Here you go. I'm counting on you.
We used to make them at Grandpa's place too!
Is that so?
I want my own kitchen knife.
Isn't it a little too soon for you?
They have a version for kids too.
Seriously?
I'll think about it.
All right, finish eating.
We have to leave soon.
Isn't that baby cute?
Yeah.
I'm Kawachi, a relative of Kaga Rin-san's father.
Rin-san... Rin and I are currently living together.
I see.
Um, you are Yoshii Masako-san,
Rin's mother, right?
Um...
Me?
Well, yes.
I'd like to talk to you face to face.
A location close to you is fine,
so please pick a place where we could meet.
Place? Um...
Let's see... Near the shopping district-
Sorry, but I don't know where you live.
Kaga Rin
They're so cute!
Nice job making them, Mom.
You made this flower too?
That's right. It's called embroidery.
It's awesome!
I'll teach you how to do it when you're a little older.
Really?
You have a talent for this stuff, Rin-chan.
So, what do you plan to do?
I won't know until I meet her.
Well then, I'll leave Rin to you.
Daikichi.
This is important.
Take your time talking to her.
Mom has been looking forward to spending time with Rin-chan too.
This really is close to Grandpa's house.
Welcome!
Table for one?
Another person will be joining me.
Non-smoking.
You're going to spill it!
The stress just keeps building up.
I know what you mean.
One American, please.
Right, one American.
Will that be all?
Yes.
Nice, Saionji-sensei!
As expected from you.
All that's left is to give each character two or three traumas.
Isn't that a bit too much?
No, I think that would make it perfect.
This is weird.
She went to all that trouble to hide her existence at Grandpa's place,
but she still lives so close by.
I'll leave the rest to you, Sensei.
Thank you for your help.
Not very smart for someone who ran away.
Mom, I have to pee!
Right, just hold it for a bit.
Hello. Where are you right now?
I'm already in the restaurant.
Souichi-san!
No, I'm his grandson.
She's like a little kid.
I'm sorry about earlier.
You look so much like him.
Not a problem.
Someone else said the same thing to me recently.
However,
Souichi-san looked a lot kinder.
I brought a picture of Rin.
Thank you.
It was taken at the beginning of this year
during a rice-cake cooking competition at school.
She looks like a young lady already.
I heard someone call you "Sensei" earlier.
You were watching?
But the name is-
That's my pen name.
I'm sorry. I was up all night yesterday because of a deadline,
so I kind of spaced out.
Did you leave Rin because of your work?
Um...
It seems you made Rin believe that you were a maid.
Was that from when she was a baby?
It's true that my work was the reason,
but it's also true that I was Souichi-san's maid.
I was determined not to think of Rin as my daughter even while I was pregnant.
I-I'm sorry. I don't understand.
Back then, my books didn't sell.
Right when I got a major assignment, I found out I was pregnant.
It's not the kind of work you can do while raising a kid,
but Souichi-san insisted that I have the baby regardless.
I'd either be working or sleeping and got fatter by the day.
Oddly enough,
when Rin was born, she was so cute that I loved her a lot.
She thinks that's weird?
That's why, while telling myself I wasn't her mother,
I tried my best to balance Rin and work.
It was tough, what with having work in the morning,
and having to go out at night for meetings.
I'd have to stay up late at night,
which was physically impossible.
I heard that Rin would stay with you in your apartment at night.
Yes.
Did you go out at night, even then?
Well, it would be pretty late.
Rin was asleep, so I'd step out for a bit.
Sometimes I'd have Souichi-san look after her too.
Rin still wakes up in the middle of the night once in a while.
Didn't you ever think about how she would feel
in a situation like that when no one's beside her?
Then how was I supposed to raise a kid on my own?
That's why my grandfather wanted you to be part of the family, right?
Do you have anything against Rin continuing to live with me?
No.
I'm not her mother anymore,
so I don't have the right to decide her future.
Even though it's a fact that Rin was once in your belly?
That has nothing to do with this!
How do you feel about Rin?
Is she important to you or not?
I don't know.
Um, I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
When she goes to school, please let her use your surname.
My surname?
If her surname is different from her guardian's,
I'm sure she'll have a rough time.
Can you promise me that?
I understand your feelings,
but I can't promise that.
She's always been Kaga Rin.
I don't think it's that easy to just change someone's name.
As a woman,
I don't have any love or attachment for my surname.
It might change someday anyway.
Rin is a girl too,
so I bet she feels the same way.
But Rin is only six.
Besides, what I'm trying to say is...
That's just your opinion-
There's only one important thing.
That is the name "Rin," which she got from Souichi-san.
That is all. Excuse me.
Um...
As a man, I don't really understand what you're saying,
but I can talk to Rin about it.
Talk to her about it?
Making such a little girl decide...
Isn't that too cruel-
I...
I'm thinking about what's best for Rin.
Besides, deciding without her consent would be cruel.
I have to listen to Rin's opinion first.
After that, we will make the decision together
and let you know what happens.
She sounds like a bad person.
Definitely.
Besides, abandoning such a cute, little child...
It defies reason!
Well, she does worry about Rin.
It's just that she's a little weird,
or rather, she isn't aware of getting others involved.
What are you saying?
It's only natural for a mother to worry about her daughter.
If she really was worried, she'd want to see her kid!
Now, now. She must've had a good reason.
Here you go.
I wonder what Grandpa ever saw in her.
It's a little too late to be thinking about that now.
It's just that she wants Rin to use my surname when she starts school.
Oh, I agree with that too.
It's obviously better for a kid to have the same surname as her guardian.
I understand that, but...
How am I supposed to explain that to Rin?
She already has a name of her own.
Well, she's a girl,
so her surname will change when she gets married anyway.
That again?
What do you mean, "again"?
It's better for her to use our surname at school,
so no one says something to hurt her.
You think she'll understand all that?
A lot of stuff will happen once she gets into elementary school.
That's just how it is.
In that case, I'll adopt Rin.
Wha...
If she's okay with it,
then she really will be Kawachi Rin.
Yeah, that's more natural.
Don't just casually talk about something that important!
I'm not being casual!
This matter needs to be settled anyway!
Who cares when you settle it?!
Now, now, now.
It's not the same!
Yes, it certainly is!
I'm not passing the baton to someone else anyway.
That would be the worst thing I could do to Rin.
If it's for Rin, I'll take the plunge.
Kid's
knife
Here.
Kid's
knife
This is for me?
Yeah, it's yours.
But you're only allowed to use it when I'm with you, okay?
As long as you keep that promise, you're allowed to use it.
Okay!
I'll make some curry!
Are you serious?
Today!
Why not tomorrow?
Huh?
Do I move it towards me or away from me?
Let me see.
You do it like this.
Daikichi, you're good at this!
I've lived alone for a long time, you see.
Here, give it a shot.
Take your time with it.
Don't drink the bath water.
I won't.
Now, sink your shoulders in, and count to ten.
One... two...
three even, four, only, five, pentagram, six, crocodile, seven, eighnine...
three... four... five...
Daikichi, you're too slow!
six...
Don't eat it too fast.
Okay.
Say, Rin.
What?
Never mind.
The curry you made is delicious.
Do you need to do it that many times?
Not really.
You know,
I'm not your dad.
I know.
But I'm not your brother either.
No one thinks that.
I'm trying to make a point.
So, what am I to you?
Daikichi.
That's just my name.
Listen, if you're not against it...
Well, how should I say this...
If I were...
If I were to become your father...
What do you think?
You would... be my father?
If that were to happen, your name would become Kawachi Rin.
Kawachi... Rin.
No way.
"No way"?
Don't you think it'd be better if you had a father?
My father is Grandpa.
I like my name.
It's the same as Grandpa's,
so it's important.
I see.
I like you just the way you are.
Daikichi?
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
This is just sweat!
It's only March.
Be quiet! Just open your mouth!
I did, but you were crying!
I said I wasn't crying!
A little higher.
Okay.
This place will always be your home, okay?
Yeah.
Congratulations On Graduating
From Nursery School
I understand.
You're gonna get fat, you know.
It's fine. I'm a bad person anyway.
Can I have one?
No.
That's only for babies!
Sayaka-chan said that too.
Of course not!
There are times when adults want to be held too.
Why?
I don't know either.
Is it still okay, even after becoming a first grader?
Sure it is.
I'll hold you in my arms no matter how old you are.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry!
I should've given you a hug that time.
The next time you cry, I'll give you a hug.
What on Earth...
No worries!
Am I raising Rin, or is she raising me?
I often wonder about that.